人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：灰灰是菇凉  Michael  王小麦  莎友友  小早  静静的木头  那时花开
超感警探
第六季
第六集
时间轴：Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹   校对：灰灰是菇凉
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：灰灰是菇凉
《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The mentalist"...
我们得找到基拉·汀斯利
We need to find kira tinsley.
她要么跟血腥约翰是一伙的
She either works for Red John,
要么马上就要成为他下一个目标了
or she's about to become his next victim.
谁干的  告诉我
Who did this to you? Tell me.
简  她说什么了
Jane, what did she say?
她说血腥约翰左肩膀有个纹身
She told me Red John has a tattoo on his left shoulder--
三个点
Three dots.
这是我的筹码
That's my leverage.
马里布
加利福尼亚  马里布  简的家宅
-简  -喂  里斯本
- Jane. - Hello, Lisbon.
简  别这么做  别扔下我这么做
Jane, don't do this, not without me.
对不起
Listen, I'm sorry.
简  求你了  你身处险境
Jane, I am begging you. You're in danger!
没事的  我不会有事的
I-it's gonna be okay. I-I'm gonna be okay.
不可能
No, you're not.
你这样做是在自寻死路
You do this, and you're throwing your life away.
再见  里斯本
Bye, Lisbon.
简  别这样
Jane... no.
两天前
星期二
纹身吗
A tattoo?
对
Yes.
我们可以用那个来确定血腥约翰的身份
That we can use to identify Red John?
-是的  -太好了
- Yes. - That's great.
所以我们只要一个个检查疑犯
So all we have to do is check each one of the suspects
看哪个人身上就纹身就行了
one by one until we find out who has the tattoo.
不行
No.
为什么不行
Why not?
血腥约翰还不知道我发现纹身的事
Red John doesn't know I know about the tattoo.
好吧
Okay.
所以如果我们去查他们
So if we start checking suspects,
很有可能血腥约翰会发现此事
it's very likely that red john will find out.
然后在我们还没机会接近他的时候就销声匿迹
And disappear before we have a chance of getting him.
正是如此
Exactly.
那你们打算怎么办
Then what do you want to do?
把五名疑犯同时
Gather all five suspects together
集合到一个地方
at the same place, same time,
然后再检查是否有纹身
And then start checking for the tattoo.
如何才能做到呢
And how do we do that?
就直接叫他们过来
We'll ask them.
你觉得他们会同意吗
And you think they'll agree?
没打算给他们选择的余地
Wasn't planning on giving them a choice.
就算成行了  还有个问题
Even so, there's a problem.
布莱特·斯特尔斯因两起谋杀
Bret Stiles--he's wanted by the F.B.I.
被联调局通缉
in connection to two homicides.
对  二十多年前的悬案
Yeah. Cold cases from over 20 years ago.
真的假的
You're kidding,
都过去那么多年了
after all this time,
联调局现在才跟进吗
the F.B.I. is moving in now?
他们肯定是有了什么新的
Well, they must have found something new--
-法医证据  目击证人  -那斯特尔斯在哪
- forensics, a witness. Well, where's Stiles?
关键就是这个  没人知道他在哪
Well, that's the thing. Nobody knows,
连联调局也不知道  斯特尔斯几周前就消失了
Not even the F.B.I. Stiles disappeared weeks ago.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
怎么找
How?
不知道  但我们会找到他的
I don't know, but we'll find him.
必须找到他
We have to.
我配合你的计划
I'm on board with your plan.
好
Good.
有个条件
On one condition.
你揭露血腥约翰身份的时候我要在场
I want to be there when you reveal Red John.
好的
Okay.
我说真的
Seriously.
-我说了好的  -说是说了  但你说的肯定不算数
- I said okay. - Yeah, but you didn't mean it.
是吗  你怎么知道
Did I not? Uh, how can you tell?
这事没有商量的余地  简
This is non-negotiable, Jane.
我百分百同意
I agree 100%.
我认为我之前说得够清楚了  探员们
I think I've made myself clear, agents.
我完全不知道布莱特·斯特尔斯在哪
I have no knowledge of Bret Stiles' whereabouts.
对  你说了
Yes,
而我们也表达得很清楚了  你这说法我们不买账
and we've made it clear that we're not buying it.
斯特尔斯把天眼组织的领导权留给了你
Stiles leaves you in charge of Visualize,
但他却没有告诉你他躲藏在哪里吗
but he keeps you in the dark about where he's hiding?
这根本说不通
Doesn't make sense.
斯特尔斯自始至终
Stiles has and always will
都将教徒的需要放在他自己之前
put the church's needs before his own.
这次也一样
This time is no different.
他不想让我知道是因为他想保护我
He doesn't want me to know because he wants to protect me.
也因为他不想被人找到
And because he doesn't want to be found.
我不觉得布莱特·斯特尔斯担心是否会被找到
I doubt Bret Stiles is worried about being found.
你看起来很有信心
You seem confident.
这叫信仰
Call it faith.
斯特尔斯在我们这个
You see, Stiles' time
现实世界里的时间  是有限的
in our... reality is limited.
就在我们说话的这会
As we speak,
他正在做好心理和身体上的准备
he's preparing his mind and body
以摆脱我们这个物质世界的束缚
for a departure from the confines of our material world.
他要死了吗
He's dying?
这是非常天真
That is a very naive,
非常无知的想法
very ignorant way of looking at it.
布莱特·斯特尔斯不会死
Bret Stiles is not dying.
他也不能死
Bret Stiles cannot die.
他是要将自己提升到一个新的高度
He is elevating himself to another plane,
我们这种道行不够的
one lesser men like ourselves
要非常艰难才能触碰到这种高度
can only strive to reach.
显然我们中有人对此是无法理解的
And one some of us obviously can't comprehend.
咖啡  加了一份奶油  一份糖
Coffee--one cream, one sugar.
谢了  拉塞尔
Thanks, Russell.
你要准备好了的话鉴证小组就要过来了
Forensics is here when you're ready.
让他们过来吧
Send them over.
帮我查明他的身份  好吗
Get his I.D. for me, will you?
你知道我怕高
You know how I am about heights.
没问题
Sure.
对了  有人来找你
Oh, and, uh, someone's here to see you.
谢了
Thanks.
血腥约翰的案子有了重大突破
There's been a breakthrough in the Red John investigation.
我得到了一些新线索
I have some new information.
非常重要的线索
Some very significant information.
好吧  是什么
Okay. What is it?
不  现在还不能说
No, no. Not yet.
我不知道能信任谁
I'm not sure who I can trust.
我甚至不知道能不能信任你
I'm not even sure I can trust you.
血腥约翰有一些位高权重的同伙
Red John has some very powerful allies.
派翠克  不是吧
Patrick, come on.
好吧  但不能在这说
Okay, but not here.
周四晚上八点见面
Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night.
周四  为什么
Thursday? Why?
我需要时间找一个安全的见面地点
I need time to find a safe place to meet.
好吧  在哪见
Fine. Where?
等到了那天再告诉你
I'll let you know the day of.
太扯淡了
This is crazy.
我已经犯过很多次错误了
I've made the mistake of underestimating Red John
总是低估了血腥约翰
a number of times now.
我不想再犯这种错误了
I don't want to make that mistake again.
如果你想知道线索  就要听我的
If you want the information, it's on my terms.
好吧
Okay.
周四晚上
Thursday night.
我是麦卡利斯特警长
This is Sheriff McAllister.
警长吗  我是派翠克·简
Sheriff? Patrick Jane.
你好  派翠克  最近怎么样
Hello, Patrick. How are things?
很好  很好
Good. Good.
-我打电话是有事想问你  -问吧
- I'm calling because I had a question. - Shoot.
上个月我去纳帕谷的时候
Last month when I was in Napa,
你说听任我的调遣
you said that you were at my disposal.
是的  我记得
Yes, I remember.
你说话算数吗
Did you mean what you said?
我觉得我是讲信用的人
I like to think I'm a man of my word.
绝对是
Oh, I don't doubt it.
但我能指望你帮我个忙吗
But can I count on you for your help?
可以吗
Can I count on you?
当然
Of course.
周四晚上八点我需要你的帮助
Thursday night at 8:00 I'll need your help.
没问题
Well, then you've got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
等到那天我再告诉你去哪
I'll let you know where to be the day of.
派翠克
Patrick?
什么事
Yeah?
是关于血腥约翰的事  对吧
This is about Red John, isn't it?
周四晚上见
Thursday night.
他们准备好了  先生
They're ready for you, sir.
谢谢你  伊夫林
Thank you, Evelyn.
还有  这是给您的
Also, this came for you.
派翠克·简正在找你
今晚你们在这里
You are here tonight
将见证我升天
to witness my ascension.
从这个世界  飞升到
My ascension from this world
一个世外的天地
to a world beyond.
不要为我哀悼  我的子民
Do not mourn me, my children,
因为这并非逝去
for this is not a passing,
而是启程
but a departure.
我保证
And I promise...
我  将
I... will...
归来
return!
星期三
听我说  唐  你养的不是一个情妇
Listen to me, Don, you don't have a mistresst.
那只是一个想要报复你  会毁掉你的疯子
You have a vindictive screwball who's about to ruin your life.
算你走运  我的工作就是解决问题
Yes, well, it's very lucky for you my job is to fix problems,
你现在要做的是
so here's what you're gonna do.
你要给她开张支票
You are gonna write her a check--
给她很大一笔钱
It is gonna be a very big check--
然后祈祷这事就这么完了
And then you are gonna pray that this problem goes away.
如果还没完  也别担心  唐
If it doesn't, don't worry, Don.
有很多种办法可以让一个女人闭嘴  别担心
There are plenty of ways to keep a woman quiet, OK?
好了
All right.
我挂了
I gotta go. All right.
你迟到了
You're late.
我也很高兴见到你  特蕾莎
It's good to see you, too, Teresa.
你好  请给我来一杯黑咖
Uh, excuse me, can I get coffee, black, please?
谢谢
Thanks.
早上八点把我叫来干什么
So why am I here at 8:00 a.m.?
我有个调查需要你的帮助
I need help with an investigation.
什么调查
What investigation?
这不重要
It's not important.
是么  如果你找我帮忙那这就很重要
Really? It is if you want my help.
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
得了吧  特蕾莎  我还不了解你吗
Come on, Teresa. I know you better than that.
你和简对血腥约翰的调查
What, you and Jane got something going on
有进展了吧
with the Red John case?
也许吧
Maybe.
"也许"  是啊
"Maybe." Yeah, right.
为什么要搞得这么神秘
What is with all the secrecy?
说真的  为什么要瞒着我
Seriously, why are you always holding out on me?
你们该不会觉得我是血腥约翰吧
You don't think I'm Red John, do you?
你们就是这么想的  是吗
You do, don't you?
听着
Tell you what.
你要想找我问话  那就逮捕我
You want to question me, you arrest me.
否则就别把我扯进来
Otherwise, you leave me the hell out of this.
坐下
Sit down.
坐
Sit.
如果问不管用  我不问了
If asking's not gonna work, I won't ask.
你已经不为加调局工作了
You're no longer with the CBI.
你现在无法得到执法人员所能得到的保护了
You don't get the same protection law enforcement gets.
-怎么  你威胁我  -不是我  是简
- What, you threatening me? - No, Jane is.
他明天晚上想见你一面
He wants to see you tomorrow night.
你如果不去  他就会认为你是血腥约翰
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
然后他会找你麻烦的  雷
And, Ray, he will come after you.
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
你了解简的  你知道他身上发生了什么
You know Jane. You know what happened to him.
你也知道血腥约翰对他做了些什么
You know what Red John did to him.
如果是我  我不会拿这个试探他
If I were you, I wouldn't test him.
我可不怕派翠克·简
I'm not afraid of Patrick Jane.
那去和他见一面又有什么关系
Well, what's the problem with showing up?
我如果去了  你和简
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
就不会再怀疑我是血腥约翰了吗
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
以后绝对不会了
For once and for all.
什么时间
What time?
八点
08:00.
我还没说完
I'm not done.
还有件事
There's one more thing that I need.
你就是在折磨我
You're killing me here.
-斯特尔斯  -他怎么了
- Stiles. - Yeah?
-他在哪儿  -我帮不了你
- Where is he? - I can't help you.
得了吧  雷
Come on, Ray,
你都为天眼组织工作这么多年了
you've been with Visualize for years.
我不想抓他  我只想跟他谈谈
I don't want to arrest him. I just want to talk to him.
你帮我这个忙  算我欠你的
You do this, and I will owe you.
你现在在做的事
And in your line of work,
迟早你会需要我帮忙的
sooner or later you're gonna need a favor.
雷·哈弗内说斯特尔斯
So Ray Haffner told me that Stiles uses
有一架私人飞机供其往来国内不被发现
a private jet to move around the country undetected.
机主是一个名叫莱恩·帕克斯的人
Belongs to a guy named Ryan Parks.
帕克斯  知道了  我去查
Parks. Got it. I'll check it out.
简到局里了吗
Has Jane been in yet?
没  没见他的消息
No, I haven't heard from him.
加州  帕罗奥多  帕罗奥多机场
拉莫特先生吗
Mr. Lamotte?
是我  有什么可效劳的
Yeah? Can I help you?
周探员  瑞斯比探员  加调局的
Agents Cho and Rigsby from the CBI.
我们想请你回答几个问题
We were wondering if you could answer a few questions for us.
好的
Sure.
昨晚有一架G6私人飞机降落在这里
A G6 landed here late last night,
注册尾号为M550MT
tail number M550MT.
大约十一点左右
It would have been around 11:00.
我记得  怎么了
I remember. What about it?
你知道飞机上的人是谁吗
Do you know who was on the flight?
不知道  私人飞机不需要
No. Private aircraft aren't required
提供乘客名单
to provide passenger manifests.
你有碰巧见到有谁从飞机上下来吗
Did you happen to see anyone who was getting off the plane?
没有  抱歉
No. Sorry.
不过  有汽车服务公司的人来接他
Oh, but whoever it was had a car service pick him up.
他们可能帮得上忙
They might be able to help you.
你不会正好知道那个汽车服务公司的名字吧
You don't happen to have the name of that car service, by any chance?
知道
Yes, I do.
汽车服务公司那边怎么说
So what happened with the car service?
他们说昨晚从机场接到了一个
Well, they said that they picked up a silver-haired man
操着英国口音的银发男人
with a British accent from the airport last night.
-斯特尔斯  -我们也是这么想的
- Stiles. - We think so.
那他去哪了
Well, where'd he go?
地址是厄瓜多尔领事馆
The address was for the Ecuadorian Consulate
在旧金山
in San Francisco.
好样的  你们俩去查查看
Good job. You two go and check it out.
我说  范佩尔  不如你一个人去吧
You know what? Van Pelt, why don't you go alone?
斯特尔斯喜欢你
Stiles likes you.
也许我们能利用这个优势
Maybe we can use that to our advantage.
有什么问题吗
Is...there a problem?
-没有  -没有
- Uh, no. - No.
-我没问题的  -我知道
- I'll be fine. - I know.
-职责所在  -我知道
- It's my job. - I know.
我爱你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
里斯本
Hey, Lisbon.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我就干点跑腿的活
Oh, just running some errands.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
好极了  有事吗
Yeah, right as rain. What's up?
哈弗内答应了
Haffner's in.
很好  斯特尔斯那边怎样了
Good. What about Stiles?
范佩尔好像瞄准他的位置了
Van Pelt may have a bead on his location.
她正在查
She's checking it out now.
这样就还剩一个血腥约翰案疑犯要约谈
That leaves one more Red John suspect left to talk to.
是的  伯特仑
Yes. Bertram.
我正往他办公室走呢
I'm on my way to his office.
-咱们那边见吗  -好
- You want to meet me there? - All right.
加利福尼亚  旧金山  厄瓜多尔领事馆
格蕾斯·范佩尔
Grace Van Pelt.
再次见到你真是太好了
Well...how lovely to see you again.
请坐吧
Well...so, please sit.
这次有何贵干呢
What do I owe this pleasure?
是简
Jane.
他需要你帮个忙
He needs a favor.
差你来  他可真聪明
Oh. Clever, him, sending you.
那么我到底能为派翠克·简做些什么呢
So exactly what can I do for Patrick Jane?
他想见见你
He would like to meet with you.
明天晚上八点
Tomorrow night at 8:00.
自我们上次一别  你变样了
You've changed since we last met.
你结婚了
You're married.
是的
Yes.
别跟我说你嫁给那个只会傻笑的呆子了
Oh, don't tell me you married that genial oaf.
好吧  恭喜你
Oh. Oh, well. Congratulations.
谢谢你
Yeah. Thank you.
那么  你会去见简吗
So...will you meet with Jane?
你知道的
Ah...you know,
能见他我再高兴不过了
nothing would please me more than to meet with him.
我真的很乐意  但是
I mean, really, I would love to. But...
很不幸的是  鉴于我现在的境况
unfortunately, my circumstances--
好像不太能成行
it's probably not gonna happen.
你是说因为联邦调查局吗
You mean because of the F.B.I.?
你功课做得不错嘛
Mm. You have been doing your homework.
他们不知道我来了
They don't know I'm here.
所以他们也就不知道你在这里
Which means they don't know you're here.
但你要是不肯见简  他们就会知道了
But they will if you don't agree to meet with Jane.
你的确变了  不是吗
You have changed, haven't you?
你去过厄瓜多尔吗
Have you ever been to Ecuador, by any chance?
没有
No.
我很多很多年以前
I was there--oh, god, years and years ago
在那传教来着
doing missionary work. Uh...
那里的人很不错
lovely people.
不过有个年轻人
But there was a young man there...
他很穷  但野心勃勃
he was underprivileged, ferociously ambitious.
我在他身上看到了些东西
I saw something in him.
所以我决定试着帮帮他
So I decided to try and help him.
我帮他付学费
You know, I-I paid for his school fees,
之类的
that sort of thing.
其实也没什么  但你猜怎么着
N-nothing really much, but wouldn't you know it?
这么多年之后
All these years later,
那小子已经是国务部长了
that same man is now Minister of State.
我很为他高兴
I'm happy for him.
他邀请我住在这豪华的领事馆里
Anyway, he invited me to stay in this palatial consulate.
在这一片小小的外国领土上
This morsel of foreign soil.
外国领土  如你所知
Foreign soil, of which, as you know,
是不受你们加调局  联调局
is outside the jurisdiction of you, the F.B.I.,
与任何美国法律管辖的
or U.S. law enforcement.
所以呢  格蕾斯  你的威胁不管用
So, you see, Gracie, your idle threats are just that.
当然  很高兴能再见到你
Well, it's been so lovely seeing you again.
帮我跟简问个好
Please give my best to Mr. Jane.
出去的时候随手关门
Close the door on your way out!
没事的
It's gonna be fine.
谢谢啊  我感觉轻松多了
Thanks. I feel a lot better.
进来
Come on in.
长官  案子有突破了
We've made a breakthrough, sir.
-什么案子  -血腥约翰案
- In... - The Red John case.
我们马上就能确定凶手了
We're close to identifying him.
真是个好消息
Well, then this is fantastic news.
都这么多年了
After all these years. Y-you--
你真的确定了吗
You really think you've got him?
是的
I do.
一旦你们有了切实答案要立刻告诉我
I'll know the second you have something concrete.
是的  长官
You will, sir.
此案结束的时候我要在场
And I want to be there when you end this.
就等您这句话呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
喂  是我
Yeah, it's me.
我刚和派翠克·简谈了点有趣的事
I just had a very interesting conversation with Patrick Jane.
伯特仑那边怎么样
How'd it go with Bertram?
上钩了  斯特尔斯那边呢
He's in. What about Stiles?
-不太好  -你找到他了吗
- Not so good. - Did you find him?
找到了
Yes.
那还有什么问题
Then what's the problem?
他住在厄瓜多尔领事馆里
He's at the Ecuadorian consulate.
只要他在里面  我们就动不了他
As long as he's there, we can't touch him.
你打算怎么办
What do you want to do?
我来对付斯特尔斯
I'll handle Stiles.
他不会也不必跟你出来
He's not gonna come with you. He doesn't have to.
相信我的说服力
I'll be persuasive.
那是什么
What is that?
霰弹枪
A shot gun?
火力够大了吗
You sure it's big enough?
关于明天晚上的事  我们得谈谈
We need to talk about tomorrow night.
我已经告诉你了
I've already told you.
先听我说完
Just hear me out, please.
你不希望我在场
You don't want me to be there.
是的
No, I don't.
你不希望我在场是因为你觉得
You don't want to be there because you think
我会阻止你杀血腥约翰
I'm gonna try and stop you from killing red john.
你的意思是你不会吗
Are you saying that you won't?
我想说的是
What I'm saying is some men--
像血腥约翰这种禽兽
men like Red John--
根本连上庭受审的资格都没有
they don't deserve a trial. They don't deserve a jury.
这种人就该就地正法
They deserve what they have coming to them.
等等  让我搞搞清楚
Wait, l-let me get this straight.
你在执法部门干了快二十年
After close to 20 years working in law enforcement,
竟然就这么改变原则了吗
you're just-- you're changing your mind?
在血腥约翰案上吗  没错
About Red John? Yes.
我很惊讶  里斯本
I'm surprised, Lisbon.
怎么  你不相信我吗
What, you don't believe me?
当然不会
Heavens, no.
你是我认识的最诚实的人
You're the most honest person I know.
这种事情上  你绝不会骗我的
You would never lie, not about something like this.
是不是
Right?
当然
Right.
那明晚见
Tomorrow night then.
明晚见
Tomorrow night.
星期四
派翠克  我亲爱的孩子
Patrick, dear boy.
近来还好吗
Well, how are you?
我不是你的孩子
Well, I'm not your boy.
我明白了  那么说你不是来找我聊天的
Oh, I see. So this is not a social meeting, eh?
明晚八点你要来见我
You're gonna meet me tonight at 8:00.
-派翠克  -不  你听我说
- Patrick. - No, you listen to me.
我要你明晚八点来见我
You're gonna meet me tonight at 8:00,
否则等到我再回来找你
Or I'm gonna come back here, and when I do,
就算这是领事馆也保不了你
you will need more than these walls to keep you safe.
威胁我吗
Threats?
这不是你的风格啊
That's so out of character.
我说的话句句当真
I mean every word of it.
确实
Yes.
我相信你
I believe you do.
可是派翠克
But you see, Patrick,
将死之人还怕什么死亡威胁呢
a dying man does not fear death.
省省吧
Oh, please.
装模作样骗骗你那些信徒还行
This charade might work on your disciples.
骗我就算了吧
It doesn't work on me.
你太高估我了
You think too highly of me.
非常不幸的是
Unfortunately,
这次不是装的了
it's not a charade.
你还剩多长时间
How long have you got?
已经扩散到血液了
It's spread to the blood.
已经无药可医了  我不知道
There's nothing they can do. I don't know...
也许两周  也许一个月
Two weeks, a month.
听我说
You see...
这不是针对你
it's not personal.
只是现在
It's just that...
时间对我来说太宝贵了
my time now is very precious.
今晚我还是需要你来
I'm still gonna need you tonight.
看在上帝的份上  为什么
For god sake, why?
有什么事如此重要
What's so damned important?
血腥约翰
Red John.
我终于接近他了
I'm close.
前所未有的接近
Closer than I've ever been.
血腥约翰
Red John...
听着
Look...
今晚我若能去见你
nothing would give me more pleasure
那是再高兴不过了
than to be with you there tonight.
但是
But?
我的情况比你想象的复杂
There's more to this than you know.
我被困在这儿还有别的原因
There's--there's more keeping me here.
联调局吗
The F.B.I?
对  事实正是如此
Yeah, as a matter of fact.
他们跟我到这里
You know, they tracked me here.
就等着我出去
They're just waiting for me to leave
然后逮捕我
so they can arrest me.
不是我想呆在这儿的
Look, I'm not choosing to stay here,
我被困住了
but I'm trapped.
这么说联调局是唯一的问题了
So the F.B.I's the only thing that's keeping you here?
注意  前门有动静
Eyes up, we've got movement at the front entry.
是天眼组织的车
That's a Visualize car.
他们在偷偷往外转移什么人
I think they're sneaking someone out.
随时准备行动
Get ready to move.
立即行动  行动  上
Go now! Go! Go! Go!
-不许动  -不许动
- Don't move! - Don't move!
把手放在方向盘上
Hands on your steering wheel!
把手放在我们能看见的地方
Keep your hands where we can see 'em.
你们好  先生们
Hello. Gentlemen.
有什么能为你们效劳的吗
Something I can help you with?
斯特尔斯入局了
Stiles is in.
我们该出发了
We'd better get going.
我们可有很长一段车程
We've got a long drive ahead of us.
把他带走
Take him.
晚上八点  马里布  雪松街1309号见  走便道
信息已发送
那么萨城警局只有等着了
Well, then Sac P.D.'s just gonna have to wait.
我不想用职权压人
Look, I-I don't wanna pull rank...
但若有必要我会的
but I will.
凯文  回头我再打给你
Kevin, I gotta call you back.
我需要一辆车
I'll be needing a car.
我们要去干什么
What are we doing?
我想看看日落
I want to see the sunset.
里斯本  有些话我想跟你说
There's something I want to tell you, Lisbon.
很早以前就应该跟你说了
Something I should have said a long time ago.
谢谢你做的一切
I want to thank you for everything that you've done.
晚点再谢也不迟
You can thank me later.
不
No, I...
我必须现在就说
I need to say this now.
你
You have...
不知道你对我意味着什么
no idea what you've meant to me.
你对我有多重要
What you mean to me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
差点忘了  我有个惊喜给你
I almost forgot. I have a surprise for you.
在这等我
Wait here.
简
Jane?
Jane!
马里布
加利福尼亚  马里布  简的家宅
停车
Hey! Stop!
请停车
Please.
我叫特蕾莎·里斯本
My name is Teresa Lisbon.
我是加州调查局探员
I am an agent with the California Bureau of Investigation,
现在我要征用你的车
and I need to borrow your car.
这是紧急情况
It's an emergency.
什么  不行
What?! No way.
立即下车  快
Get out. Now. Come on.
快
Come on.
太过分了
This is outrageous.
我要报警
I'm calling the police.
好主意  谢谢
Good idea. Thanks.
-简  -喂  里斯本
- Jane. - Hello, Lisbon.
简  别这么做  别扔下我这么做
Jane, don't do this, not without me.
对不起
Listen, I'm sorry.
简  求你了  你身处险境
Jane, I am begging you. You're in danger!
没事的
I-it's gonna be okay.
我不会有事的
I-I'm gonna be okay.
不可能
No, you're not.
你这样做是在自寻死路
You do this, and you're throwing your life away.
再见  里斯本
Bye, Lisbon.
简
Jane...
别这样
No.
你好  派翠克
Oh. Hello, Patrick.
我来早了吗
Am I early?
不早  来得正好  坐吧
No, no. Right on time. Have a seat.
911  您遇到了什么紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
我是加州调查局的
This is Agent Teresa Lisbon
特蕾莎·里斯本探员
with the California Bureau of Investigation.
请派警员到马里布的雪松街1309号
I need officers at 1309 Cedar Street in Malibu.
有探员需要立即支援
I have an agent who needs immediate assistance.
我让你们五个聚在一起是有原因的
I brought you five together for a reason.
有人可能知道了
Some of you may know that reason.
也有人可能猜到了
Some of you may have guessed.
你们中的一个人
But one of you here...
是血腥约翰
is Red John.
什么  在我们几个中间
What?! One of us?
我们其中之一是血腥约翰
One of us here is Red John?
真有意思
Well, that's very interesting.
-是谁  -我不知道
- Who is it? - I don't know.
我们到这来就是为了找出答案
And that's what we're gonna find out.
你是想说这个房间里的某个人
Wait, you're trying to say that one of us in this room...
是个连环杀手
is a serial killer?
-我很确定  -太荒唐了
- I know it. - No, this is crazy.
我向你保证完全不荒唐
I can assure you it's not.
我向你保证  我才不跟你在这儿胡闹
Well, I can assure you I'm not sticking around for this crap.
坐下
Sit down.
一步都别想往门口走
Do not move toward the door.
谁都不准走
No one is leaving.
放轻松  派翠克
Take it easy, Patrick.
我看起来很紧张吗
Do I look distressed?
别动
Don't.
我会开枪的
I will shoot you.
其他人也一样
That goes for the rest of you as well.
慢慢把你们的枪拿出来  放在地上
Take out your weapons slowly, place them on the floor,
推到我这边来
and push them toward me.
谢谢
Thank you.
行了  派翠克
Okay, Patrick.
够了
This is... this is enough.
该到此为止了
It's gone far enough.
不  这才刚刚开始呢
No, we're just getting started.
为这一刻  我等了十年
I've waited ten years for this moment.
多年来  血腥约翰一直很狡猾
All those years, Red John has been smart.
你们中的某个人一直很狡猾
One of you has been smart.
很谨慎  除了这次
Careful. But not this time.
这一次  你露出马脚了
This time, you made a mistake.
基拉·汀斯利死之前跟我说了件事
Kira Tinsley told me something before she passed.
她告诉我杀她的人  也就是血腥约翰
She told me that her killer-- Red John--
有个纹身
has a tattoo.
左臂上有三个点
Three dots on his left arm.
就在肩膀上
On the shoulder.
你们都得
And you all...
给我看
are gonna show me...
立刻动手
Now.
开始脱吧  快
Let's go. Come on.
对了  脱掉
That's it. Take it off.
太荒唐了
Nonsense.
很好
Very good.
不是你想得那样
It's not what you think.
-你弄错了  -住嘴
- You got it wrong. - Enough.
我不是血腥约翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  派翠克
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
看  这边
Look... here.
看
Look.
站起来
On your feet.
到他们俩那边去
Over with those two.
你们别动
You stay there.
好了  你们三个
Okay, you three...
到墙边站着  快
Over against that wall-- now.
等等  不要
Wait! No!
马里布
简
Jane!